dune.co.uk 2019-07-14

# Privacy Notice | Dune London

_Dated: May 2018. This notice has been updated to reflect your rights under new data protection laws which came into force on 25 May 2018.  _

  We are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. This Privacy Notice sets out details of the information that we may collect from you and how we may use that information.  

In this Privacy Notice, "we" or "us" refers to Dune Group Limited, a company incorporated in England and Wales (with registered number 02127866) whose registered office is at 9 Hatton Street, London, NW8 8PL, United Kingdom. We are part of The Dune Group which comprises us, Dune Holding Limited, Dune International Limited, Dune Switzerland AG and Dune Shoes Ireland Limited. Where you do provide information to another member of The Dune Group, this Privacy Notice will apply as if we or us refers to the relevant member of the group. Our website refers to www.dunelondon.com. 

  **What information do we collect?  **

We may collect the following information about you: 

• your name, age/date of birth and gender 

• your email address 

• your billing, delivery or home address and telephone numbers (including mobile numbers) 

• details of your purchases and orders  

• your online browsing activity 

• your password(s) 

• your payment card details when you make a purchase or place an order with us 

• your communication and marketing preferences 

• your location 

• your correspondence and communications with us including notes of telephone calls and webchat exchanges 

• details of reviews which you post 

• your attendance at events we run 

• your competition answers or other competition submissions 

• other publicly available personal data, including any which you have shared via a public platform (such as a Twitter feed or public Facebook page). 

This list is not exhaustive and sometimes we may need to collect additional data for the purposes set out in this Notice. Some of your personal data is collected directly, for example, when you make a purchase on our websites or enter a competition. Other personal data is collected indirectly, for example, your browsing or shopping activity. Please see our Recruitment Privacy Notice if you are applying for a role at Dune. 

We work, from time to time, closely with third parties (including, for example, business partners, sub-contractors in technical, payment and delivery services, advertising networks, analytics providers, search information providers, credit reference agencies) who provide services to us and may receive information about you from them. In particular, all card payments are provided through a trusted third party payment service provider.  Worldpay will use your information to process and manage payments to us. Please see Worldpay's [Privacy Policy](https://www.worldpay.com/uk/comprehensive-privacy-policy) for more information. We may also collect personal data from third parties who have your consent to pass your details to us. 

  **How your information is used  **

Depending on how you are interacting with us, we (and trusted partners acting on our behalf) use your personal data: 

• to fulfil contractual agreements between you and us (for example when you place an order for products through our website) 

• to manage any registered account(s) that you hold with us 

• to verify your identity 

• to respond to a query and manage other customer service interactions with you 

• to send you information about our products by post 

• for market research purposes - to better understand your needs 

• to provide you with a personalised browsing experience when using our website 

• to send you details (by phone, e-mail or SMS) of promotional offers and products and services which we think may interest you, where you have consented to this (and have not withdrawn such consent) 

• to let you know about and invite you to events 

• to administer competitions we run from time to time 

We may also use your personal data: 

• for crime and fraud prevention, detection and related purposes 

• to comply with legal and regulatory requirements 

• to assess, operate and improve our website, the services provided through it and customer services 

• where we have a legal right or duty to use or disclose your information (for example in relation to an investigation by a public authority or in a legal dispute) 

We may also use your information to create anonymous data (whereby you cannot be identified) for market profiling purposes which may be used by us and shared with other companies in The Dune Group or third parties. 

We will not share your information with third parties in order for that third party to provide direct marketing communications to you, unless you have provided your consent for such use. Such third parties will have their own policies relating to the way in which your information may be used. 

In order to make certain services available to you, we may need to share your personal data with some of our service partners. These include IT, delivery, marketing service providers and analytics and search engine providers that assist us in the improvement and optimisation of our website and customer service. 

We only allow our service providers to handle your personal data when we have confirmed that they apply appropriate data protection and security controls. We also impose contractual obligations on service providers relating to data protection and security, which mean they can only use your data to provide services to us and to you, and for no other purposes.  

  **Legal Basis for Using Your Information  **

We are allowed to use personal information only if we have a proper reason to do so. This includes sharing it with third parties in certain circumstances. The law says we must have one or more of these reasons: 

• To fulfil a contract we have with you 

• When it is our legal duty 

• When it is in our legitimate interest 

• When we have your consent 

A legitimate interest is when we have a business or commercial reason to use your information. But even then, it must not unfairly go against what is right and best for you. For example, we will use your information to action an order you have placed on-line on our website on the basis that this is a legitimate interest and is necessary to fulfil the contract.  

In general, we only rely on consent as a legal basis for processing in relation to sending direct marketing communications to customers via email or text message. 

Customers have the right to withdraw consent at any time. Where consent is the only legal basis for processing, we will cease to process data as soon as we can after consent is withdrawn. Please see the Contact section below. 

We may share your personal information with any other companies in The Dune Group and other companies in the Dune Group may share your personal information with us in order to fulfil a contract we have with you or when it is in our legitimate interest. 

  **International Transfers  **

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area (EEA) which may have lower standards of data protection. It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. Such staff may be engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of your order, the processing of your payment details and the provision of support services. By submitting your personal information, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Notice. If we do transfer information to our agents or advisers outside of the EEA, we will make sure that it is protected in the same way as if it was being used in the EEA. We’ll use one of the safeguards below. 

 Transfer it to a non-EEA country with privacy laws that give the same protection as the EEA. Our standard practice is to use ‘standard data protection clauses’ which have been approved by the European Commission for such transfers. Those clauses can be accessed here. 

Transfer it to organisations that are part of Privacy Shield. This is a framework that sets privacy standards for data sent between the US and EU countries. It makes sure those standards are similar to what is used within the EEA. 

  **How long do we keep your data?  **

We will not retain your data for longer than necessary for the purposes set out in this Privacy Notice. Different retention periods apply for different types of data. 

**Your Privacy Rights**

You have the right to contact us (see the Contact section below) in order to find out what information we hold about you (please note that a small fee may be payable) or to access or correct any information we hold about you.  You can also request the erasure of the information that we hold about you (see the Contact section below) 

 To unsubscribe from marketing emails at any time, please click on the unsubscribe link at the bottom of any marketing email and update your account preferences. You may also contact us to inform us if you do not wish to receive any marketing materials from us. Please see the Contact section below. 

  Our website may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates. These websites have their own privacy policies and we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal information to these websites. 

  **Cookies  **

Our website uses cookies. Cookies are small files stored on your computer's hard drive which are used to collect information about your visit to the website. Cookies help to provide users with a good experience when browsing our website and also allow us to improve our website. 

While there are many different uses for first and third party cookies, the cookies used by us all fall into one of two main categories being either ‘functional’ i.e. needed to make sure our website runs optimally or third-party marketing/targeting cookes. 

You can find more information about the individual cookies we use and the purposes for which we use them in the table below: 

**Name of Cookie** | **Purpose of Cookie**  
---|---  
__zlcmid  | This cookie stores Zopim Live Chat ID to identify the device during visits.  
_cs_id    | Includes user ID- 13 months (according to the default value, but it can be administered on the account).  
_cs_s    | Includes number of pages viewed in the current session. Then, it is followed either by ".0" or by ".1" (the latter allowing to include a visitor to their complete session recording service: HTML background and all mouse movements). Duration- 30 minutes.  
_cs_v  ? | This cookie is used by ContentSquare to send errors to the system.  
_dc_gtm_UA-6026178-1    | This cookie collects information in an anonymous form.  
_ga    | This cookie is used to distinguish users.  
_gali  | This cookie is used to check how many unique visitors Dune has per page.  
_gid    | Used to distinguish users and stores session IDs.  
_mibhv    | This cookie is used for general purpose behaviour tracking, outside of the context of any specific campaign.  
_uetsid    | Universal event tracking, which enables Microsoft to identify end user visits to your site.  
AKA_A2  | Is an akamai cookie used by feature such as adaptive acceleration. Adaptive Acceleration(A2) is Akamai's intelligent platform that continuously applies performance optimizations with zero development effort.  
ASPSESSIONIDSWTQSBTB    | This cookie creates a non-identifiable id – which we use to track non personal information.  
crl8.fpcuid    | Is an anonymized user id for tracking engagement within your domain. We need this to provide more accurate tracking because third party cookies (our `crl8.cuid`) dropped on our domain are not supported by certain browsers, notably Safari, which is a significant portion of web traffic from mobile devices. As an example, Google Analytics uses first party cookies as well to track users and sessions.  
CurrentCustomerDune1  | This is a multi-purpose cookie that allows this Website to remember you next time you return. It will remember your login, and any items added to your basket.   
dmSessionID    | Enables to track when email campaign recipients land on the target website. This enables the effectiveness of a campaign.  
emsignupDune1    | This cookie is to stop the newsletter sign up pop-up from showing once the customer has either subscribed/clicked on the close icon in the newsletter lightbox.  
hjs_di    | A unique id that Hive assign to the device.  
hjs_ses  | A unique id representing the last browser session (re-generated after 30 minutes of inactivity).  
mmapi.store.p.0    | Contains cookies to store anonymous identifiers. Persistent storage set for a duration of one year from the visitors last visit on the site. Examples of data stored; customer profile information, campaign data and external visitor IDs.  
mmapi.store.s.0  ? | Session storage set for the duration of the browser session. Stores the following data; postponed actions, personalisation criteria and campaign data.  
msc6223  | This cookie contains all first party cookies detailed here.   
recordID  | This cookie is a unique user identifier, which enables persistent linking of behaviour on the site to a particular user and email campaign response.  
session    | This cookie is used to collect information about how visitors came to this Website. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the Website. The cookie collects information in an anonymous form, including the website where the visitor has come from.  
MPEL  | Provides automated translation and records your preferred language.  
__atuvc  | This cookie enables visitors to share content with a range of networking and sharing platforms. It stores an updated page share count.   
__atuvs  | Ensures you see the updated count if you share a page and return to it before the share count cache has updated.?  
_cs_ex    | This cookie is used by ContentSquare to exclude a visitor from data collection. Duration - 30days.  
BasketDetailsGBPDune1  | This is to store the previous currency.   
order    | This is to store the listing page order.  
recentlyViewed    | This cookie is used to generate a history of the products you have browsed while on this Website. The information may be displayed in the recently viewed section of the product detail page but is not used for any other purpose.  
securesession    | This is to keep a session active while customers are logged in.  
_gat_UA-6026178-1    | This is a pattern type cookie, where the pattern element on the name contains the unique identity number of the account or website it relates to. It is a variation of the _gat cookie which is used to limit the amount of data recordered by Google on high traffic volume websites.  
JSESSIONID    | This is a cookie in J2EE web application which is used in session tracking. It manages website resources to improve performance and the user experience.?  
stc114990    | Third party cookie which is used to store all other cookie data. The cookie name includes the site ID.  
Session%5Fsrc    | This cookie is used to collect information about how visitors arrive on this Website after interacting with marketing campaigns. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including where the visitor came from before visiting this Website.  
  
**Sub2**

We work with Sub2 Technologies Limited ("Sub2"), a company which acts as our data processor in order to maximise website user engagement. We share with Sub2 (or Sub2 accesses directly from your website use) information about you and how you use our website, including any information that you provide to us. This information is then used for the purposes of providing you with marketing which is more relevant to you and your interests.

**Content Square**

Content Square is a solution which aggregates usage and frequency data to improve user experience. Statistics created are anonymous.To be excluded from this monitoring, please click here.

**How can you control the use of cookies?**

You can amend your browser settings to block some or all cookies. To do this, follow the instructions provided by your preferred web browser. For your ease of reference we have provided the links below which provide instructions on how to remove and delete cookies for some of the more common web browsers. Please be aware that if you block cookies from the websites, some or all the website's functions may not perform as intended: 

• **[Firefox](https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/cookies-information-websites-store-on-your-computer?redirectlocale=en-US&redirectslug=Cookies)**

• **[Internet Explorer](https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies)**

• **[Google Chrome](https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en)**

• **[Safari](https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411?locale=en_US)**

Mobile phone users may have to refer to their handset manual for details on how to block cookies using their mobile browser. For more information about online behavioural advertising cookies and opt-out controls, please go to **<http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/>**. More information regarding opting out of platform based advertising can be found at **[http://appnexus.com/platform-policy#choices](https://www.appnexus.com/en/company/platform-privacy-policy)**. 

We may also use technologies, such as our own cookies, to provide you with relevant online display advertising tailored to your interests. Our marketing partner, Conversant, assists us in managing these technologies. To opt out of our cookies used for this online advertising or to submit a data subject request specific to these technologies, click _[here](http://dtmc.dunelondon.com/adinfo/choice/prod/?type=fpc&cid=2945&cname=Dune%20London&cmagic=892c3b&clogo=DuneLondon.png&loc=uk&lang=en-us)_.

If you would like to review or modify your marketing consent and preferences please click here.

**Security  **

In accordance with applicable data protection law and our own policies, we have adopted appropriate security procedures to help prevent unauthorised access to your information. 

**Children  **

Our website is not directed at children under the age of 13 and we do not knowingly collect personal information about children. If you believe we have collected personal information about your child, you may contact us as detailed in Contact below and request that we remove information about your child. 

  **Changes to our Privacy Notice  **

We may update or amend this Privacy Notice from time to time to comply with law or to meet our changing business requirements without notice to you. Any updates or amendments will be posted on this page.  

  **Contact  **

If you have any questions about how we collect, store and use your information, or you wish us to action any of the requests detailed above, please contact us by emailing customerservice@dunelondon.com or contacting us at the address below: 

  **Customer Service**

Dune Group Limited   
6-11 Elms Depot   
Cambridge Road   
Leicestershire   
LE8 6LG   
United Kingdom   
01202 560396 

**How to complain  **

You also have the right to complain to the Information Commissioner’s Office. Find out on their website how to **[report a concern](https://ico.org.uk/concerns/)**.
